2015年1月15日
雄鷹隊之家
約翰
來吧  走
Come on. Let's go.
我做了雞蛋
I made eggs.
你五點訓練結束我去接你
So I'm gonna pick you up after practice at five.
六點
Six.
我還要投籃特訓
I wanna shoot around.
那個叫查德的孩子還在找你麻煩嗎
Is that Chad kid still giving you trouble?
沒了
Nope.
好吧
Okay.
來  薩米  薩米  乖乖吃
Hey, Sammy. Sammy, come on.
我剛剛在想
So I was thinking,
不如我直接打電話給你教練吧
How about I call your coach?
不  別他媽的打
No! Hell no!
注意言辭
Language.
早上好
Good morning.
-謝謝你  -不客氣
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
早上好
Good morning.
老爸
Hey, Dad.
勇士隊明天
So, the Warriors are playing
要在俄克拉荷馬城打雷霆了
the Thunder tomorrow in Oklahoma City.
你覺得會怎麼樣
What do you think is gonna happen?
斯蒂芬·庫裡昨晚就已經得了32分了
Well, Steph Curry just scored thirty-two points last night.
所以我覺得
So what I think is that,
大廚庫裡會把他們打得落花流水
Chef Curry is gonna whomp on 'em.
說不准啊  杜蘭特打得也挺好的
I don't know. Durant's pretty good.
他可是當之無愧的MVP啊
He is the reigning MVP.
約翰
John.
飯前禱告誰來
Is somebody gonna bless our food?
行吧  那我來吧
Okay. Well, I guess I will.
主啊  儘管他一直惹我煩心
Lord, though he exasperates me to no end,
但我依然因他而感激您
I am grateful for my son.
因為我知道您將他賜給我
For I know that you've created him for a purpose,
自有您的道理
thus far only known to you.
感謝賜予我們食物  阿門
Bless this food to our bodies. Amen.
-阿門  -阿門
- Amen. - Amen.
密蘇里  聖查爾斯
我打算給你漲點零花錢
I'm thinking about raising your allowance
漲到100塊一周
to 100 bucks a week.
你在幹嘛
What are you doing?
你媽在努力引起他兒子的注意
Your mom is just trying to get her son's attention.
嗨  約翰
Hey, John.
-怎麼樣啊  夥計們  -抱一個啊
- Wassup, guys? - Hug.
你快走吧
Please go.
您好  J夫人
Hey, Mrs. J.
謝拉  艾瑪你們好啊  最近怎麼樣
Hey, Chayla. Hey, Emma. How are you girls?
活在夢中呢  J夫人
Living the dream, Mrs. J.
對了  我給你們的微信發了申請
Oh, I tried to friend you on the Instagram,
但我肯定是沒操作好
but I must be doing something wrong.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
求你快走吧  老媽
Please, just go, Ma.
我開玩笑的
I'm kidding!
玩得開心
Have a good day!
拜拜
Bye!
-你好  阿比  -你好
- Hey, Abby. - Hey.
早上好  同學們
Good morning, students.
今天是1月15日  星期四
Today is Thursday, January 15th.
年鑒委員會今天放學要開會
Yearbook committee meets after school today.
週日下午四點還有一場籃球賽
And there's a basketball game at 4:00 p.M. on Sunday.
雄鷹隊加油
Go Eagles!
沒錯  加油啊
Yeah! Go Eagles!
最後一件事
Lastly,
提醒一下週一是國定假日
a reminder that Monday is a national holiday
為了紀念馬丁·路德·金博士
in remembrance of Doctor Martin Luther King, Jr.
我和艾瑪買了週六晚上在福克斯
Emma and I got tickets to see the musical Hairspray
美國歌舞片  講述了一個愛跳舞的白人小胖妹幻想有一天能夠上節目一展舞技的故事
音樂劇《發膠明星夢》的票
at the Fox Saturday night.
哇  聽起來挺不錯
Wow! Yeah, that sounds like fun.
嘔  穿緊身衣的男人
Mmm, dudes in tights.
又不是芭蕾
It's not a ballet.
我肯定他們還是穿內褲的
Look, I'm pretty sure they'll be wearing pants.
你們打算幹什麼
So what are you guys doing?
比賽結束後我們去裡格家喝一杯
We're crashing at Rieger's after the game.
-真嫉妒  -早上好
- So jealous. - Good morning.
請起立宣誓效忠
Please stand for the Pledge of Allegiance.
把右手放在胸前
Place your right hand over your heart.
準備好了嗎  開始吧
Ready? Begin.
我宣誓擁護
I pledge allegiance to the Flag
美利堅合眾國國旗
of the United States of America
及它所代表的合眾國
and to the Republic for which it stands
一個由上帝庇佑的國家
one Nation under God
不可分割
indivisible
所有人在此均享有自由及正義
with liberty and justice for all.
我們可能也會拉點女生去
We might have some girls over, too.
-誰啊  -現在還不知道呢
- Who? - Can't say until it happens.
-但她們肯定超辣  -那必須的
- But they're hot. - Totally.
慢著  你不會說真的把
Hey, whoa. You're joking, right?
真的啊
No.
喬希·裡格  喬希·桑德斯  請安靜
Josh Rieger, Josh Sanders, quiet please.
好了同學們  繼續家人口述歷史的匯報
Okay, guys. Family oral history reports continue.
昨天我們聽了查德·格林的匯報
Yesterday we heard from Chad Green,
他們家是從五月花偷渡過來的
whose family came over on the Mayflower.
我老公他們家也是
My husband's family did as well.
他的爺爺的爺爺的爺爺還是什麼騎士呢
His great-great-grandfather was a knight of some kind.
之後我們聽了謝拉
And then we heard from Chayla,
他們家可以追溯到布魯斯的發源地
whose family lineage includes the birth of the blues
田納西的孟菲斯
in Memphis, Tennessee.
約翰  這次能請你先開始嗎
John, would you do the honors and kick us off, please?
我沒做
Didn't do it.
為什麼沒做
Why not?
我沒時間做
I didn't have time.
你要是不做作業  最後是會不及格的
If you don't do the assignment, you'll get a failing grade.
往者不可諫
"Yesterday is not ours to recover,
來者猶可追
"but tomorrow is ours to win or lose."
道蓮  你來
Doreen, you're up.
我的孩子  你完全可以信任我
"My child, you believe me for so little.
不必對你的禱詞三緘其口
"Don't be so safe in the things you pray."
-不好意思  -嗨  女士
- Oh. I'm so sorry. - Hey, lady.
-早上好啊  -早  喬伊絲
- Hey, morning. - Morning, Joyce.
我早上一點都不好
The morning got away from me.
有人想喝咖啡嗎
Does anyone need any more coffee?
-不用了  謝謝  -不了  謝謝
- No, thank you. - No, thanks.
怎麼了嗎
Hey. What passage?
一切都還好嗎
Is everything all right?
不是很好
Not exactly.
約翰的生日快到了
John's birthday is coming up,
我記得他一向不愛過生日
Oh, I remember those always been hard for him.
是啊  好像他故意隔開我們似的
Yeah. It's like he's building this wall between us.
我也恨自己什麼都做不了
And I hate myself for it.
我知道他不好過  我只是想幫忙
I know he's hurting and I just wanna fix it.
他們總是遠比看上去難對付多了
They're always so much harder to deal with
尤其是青春期的時候
once they start shaving.
之後就直接去大學了
And then they leave for college.
打起精神來
Come on.
不好意思啊  女士們
Sorry, ladies.
我確實讀了兩遍書
I did read the book twice.
我們到哪了
Uh, so where were we?
我們正聊到
Um, we were just talking about
貝絲·摩爾讓我們大膽祈禱
how Beth Moore is asking us to pray boldly.
那麼  大膽祈禱  你們覺得是什麼意思呢
So, what does it mean to you all, "to pray boldly"?
我不知道  看起來
I don't know. It just seems,
-女士們  你們好  -牧師
- Oh! Hey, ladies. - Pastor.
我們要用這個房間開職員會議
Uh, we need to use this room for a staff meeting.
你們能收拾一下嗎
You guys wrapping things up?
不行
Uh, no.
還有22分鐘
Not for another 22 minutes.
我還在開私密的女性講道會
And I have a women's ministry meeting here, back-to-back.
這樣啊
Oh, um,
我很抱歉  但我覺得用處不大
I'm sorry, but I don't think that's gonna work.
你說什麼
I'm sorry?
我在預約表上寫了兩個時間
I reserved both times on the sign-up sheet.
但是我日程上就這一個職員會
Okay. All I have on my calendar is staff meeting.
神出鬼沒的預約表在哪呢
Where's this elusive sign-up sheet?
就貼在你進來的門背後
Taped to the door that you walked in.
貼了十年了
Been going on ten years now.
其實  這是公事
Well, it's official.
現在都線上預約  女士們  詳情問麥蒂
We're going digital, ladies. See Maddy for details.
聽著  我不知道你在加州幹什麼
Listen, I don't know what you do in California,
但我開女性布道會
but I have been leading this women's ministry meeting
開了五年多了
for over five years.
我們從不取消
We don't cancel meetings...
我不知道誰算的數  喬伊絲
I don't know who's counting, Joyce,
但我來這十年了
but I've been in ministry for over ten years,
包括加州
including California.
要不這樣  你們可以去
Hey, maybe you guys could use
拐角的星巴克開會
that Starbucks around the corner?
應該不錯  對吧
That'd be fun, right?
啥  你付錢嗎
Oh, are you paying?
這我倒沒想過  但是
Well, I hadn't thought about it, but, uh,
很好
Great.
好了女士們  我們離開這吧
Okay, ladies, let's get out of here
因為我們的新牧師
because our new pastor,
有更重要的公事要忙了
has more important business to tend to.
不  不是這個意思
No, that's not true.
我很抱歉女士們  我保證下周不會這樣了
I'm sorry, ladies. I promise, this will not happen next week.
謝謝您  牧師
Thank you, Pastor.
還有  求你叫我傑森
And please, I've been asking for six months.
六個月了還不改
Call me Jason.
我們知道你叫什麼  牧師
We know, Pastor.
為什麼你對他這麼凶
Why are you so hard on him?
首先  那個髮型
That haircut, for one.
在這兒  在這兒
Right here, right here.
不錯的回彈  跑起來雄鷹們
Good rebound. Let's run, Eagle.
擋住那個前鋒
Set up that offense.
分散  分散
Spread out the floor. Spread it out.
加油  約翰  陣型
Come on, John. Set it up.
傳給我
I'm open.
就這樣
Nice, nice.
漂亮  夥計
Yes! Good job, guys.
快點  分散  防守
Come on now, spread it out. Defense.
注意手
Hands up.
防守  防守
Defense, defense.
抬起手  抬起手
Hands up! Hands up.
就是這樣
There you go.
漂亮  好球
Nice. Nice shot!
分散  就是這樣
Spread that floor. There you go.
分散  移動
Spread it out. Move it out.
快  快  那邊
Go, go, go. There they go.
小心他
Watch him.
太棒了  我就說吧
Yes! That's what I'm talking about.
現在防守好D
Hands up on D now.
很好  約翰  搶得漂亮  繼續
Very nice, John! Nice steal. There you go.
做得好  約翰
Good job, John.
防不住我就犯規嗎
Can't catch me, so you gotta foul me?
那又怎樣  傻逼
Whatever, ese.
你叫我什麼
What'd you just call me?
住手
Knock it off!
誰在動手就別想上場了
Next guy who swings is benched.
訓練結束  去洗一下
Practice is over. Wash up.
約翰  查德  過來
John, Chad, bring it here.
你們怎麼回事
What's up with you guys?
約翰搶了你的首發位置  你怎麼看
John beat you out for starting guard, Chad. Deal with it.
這只是暫時的
Temporary.
隨便  你想首發  還是換學校吧
Whatever. You wanna start, better change schools.
住嘴
Enough!
新聞快報  你還沒有進入NBA球隊
News flash. You're not in the NBA yet.
你再這樣  你就永遠也進不了球隊
And acting like that, you aren't ever gonna get there.
明白嗎
Understood?
好了  去洗一洗
All right, wash up.
約翰  等等  我跟你聊一下
John, hold up. I wanna talk to you for a minute.
我聽說你的家族歷史課業不及格
What's this I hear about you getting a failing grade
有這麼回事嗎
in your family history assignment?
有關係嗎
Why does it matter?
等你想明白了
Well, unless you figure it out,
我再讓你參加週日的比賽
I'm gonna have to bench you for Sunday's game.
-什麼  這太他媽  -停
- What? That's bull... - Hey.
隨便
Whatever.
約翰  你是個好球員
You're a good player, John.
但是現在你搞砸了
But right now you're blowing it.
你最近怎麼了
What's going on with you lately?
沒事
I'm cool.
教練  再見
I'll see ya, Coach.
訓練怎麼樣
Hey! How was practice?
還行
Fine.
學校怎麼樣
How was school?
讓我猜一猜  應該挺不錯
Oh, let me guess. Fine.
你在忙什麼
What are you working on?
口頭報告
Oral report.
也許我可以幫你
Maybe I could help.
你還留著它們幹嘛
What are you saving 'em for?
你的喬丹
Your Jordans?
在等合適的時機
When it's the right time.
好吧
Okay.
寶貝  到樓下來
Baby, come back downstairs.
你的朋友等著給你唱生日歌呢
All your friends are waiting to sing "Happy Birthday" to you.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
所有人都在等著
Everybody's waiting.
她為什麼不給我辦個派對
Why didn't she wanna have a party for me?
她為什麼不要我
Why didn't she want me?
無論如何
For what it's worth,
你有自己的目標  也有人愛著你
you have a purpose and you are loved.
史密斯先生
Mr. Smith.
很高興在這裡見到你
Nice of you to join us this morning.
我準備好做頭口匯報了
I'm ready to do my oral report.
我是約翰·史密斯
Okay, so, I'm John Smith.
你們都知道我是被收養的
Most of you know I'm adopted.
我來自於危地馬拉上一座叫聖塞爾的小鎮
I come from a small town in Guatemala called Sansare.
我不知道我的生母是誰
I don't know who my biological mother is,
我只知道她不要我了
but just that she didn't want me.
喬伊絲和布萊恩•史密斯在
Joyce and Brian Smith adopted me
我9個月大的時候收養了我
when I was nine months old.
他們出差來到了鎮上
They went down there on a missions trip
後來把我帶了回去
and they ended up coming home with me.
可能是因為我很可愛
Probably because I'm so cute.
肯定是的
But yeah,
好吧
Okay, okay.
布萊恩  在那兒
Brian, that space right there.
好  我來了  我來了
Okay, I'm on it. I'm on it.
2015年1月18日
-好了  -你好  夥計
- Okay. - Hey, guys.
約翰  你今天得和我們一起去教堂
And, John, you're sitting with us in church today.
□  誰撼動世界  □
□ Who shakes the whole earth □
□  用聖雷怒喝  □
□ With holy thunder □
□  誰讓我屏息  驚歡中敬畏  □
□ And leaves us breathless in awe and wonder □
□  榮耀的君王  超越萬王之王  □
□ The King of Glory, the King above all kings □
□  這是奇妙恩典  □
□ This is amazing grace □
□  耶  耶  □
□ Yeah, yeah □
□  這是無盡的愛  □
□ This is unfailing love □
□  耶  耶  □
□ Yeah, yeah □
□  你竟願代替我  □
□ That You would take my place □
□  噢  耶  □
□ Oh, yeah □
□  代替我  代替我  □
□ Take my place, take my place □
□  替我背負十字架  □
□ That You would bear my cross □
□  替我受罪  替我受罪  □
□ Bear my cross Bear my cross □
□  你捨下你生命  □
□ You lay down Your life □
□ You lay it down □
□  讓我得著釋放  □
□ That I would be set free □
□  釋放  釋放  釋放  □
□ Set free, set free, set free □
□  耶穌  我頌讚  □
□ Oh, Jesus, I sing for □
□  你所做的一切  □
□ All that You've done for me □
□  這恩典太神奇  □
□ This grace so amazing □
□  這就是我讚美他的原因  □
□ Whoo That's why I praise Him □
□  他們不知道我們來自哪裡  □
□ They don't know where we done came from □
□  噢  媽媽  他們熱愛和平  □
□ Oh, my momma They can't harm us □
□  舉起我的手臂  □
□ Got my arms up □
□  我們正蒙受他們的保護  □
□ While we covered in their armor □
□  我們做到了  □
□ And we done made it □
□  你們都沒聽見  但我們做到了  □
□ Y'all didn't hear me, but we made it □
□  天賜於我  我亦接受  □
□ I ain't earn it but I'll take it □
□  讓聖光照耀我的心靈  □
□ Got that light inside side of me □
□  你無需讓別人看見  □
□ That you don't need no one to see □
□  你感受到也聽得到  當我說嘿  □
□ You can feel it, you can hear it when I say Hey, hey! □
□  這是奇妙恩典  □
□ This is amazing grace □
□  耶  耶  □
□ Yeah, yeah □
□  這是無盡的愛  □
□ This is unfailing love □
□  耶  耶  □
□ Yeah, yeah □
□  你竟願代替我  □
□ That You would take my place □
□  代替我  代替我  □
□ Take my place Take my place □
□  替我背負十字架  □
□ That You would bear my cross □
□  替我受罪  替我受罪  □
□ Bear my cross Bear my cross □
□  你捨下你的生命  耶  □
□ You lay down Your life Yeah □
□  舍下它  □
□ You lay it down □
□  讓我得著釋放  □
□ That I would be set free □
□  釋放  釋放  釋放  □
□ Set free, set free, set free □
□  耶穌  我頌讚  □
□ Oh, Jesus, I sing for □
□  你所做的一切  □
□ All that You've done for me □
太精彩了
Amazing!
謝謝
Thank you.
你太棒了
You were amazing.
各位  為我們的嘉賓鼓掌
Hey, let's give it up for our guest.
羅伯  非常感謝
Rob, thank you so much.
太爽了  也謝謝你
So dope, and thank you.
舉手我看看  在座各位有誰
Show of hands. Who here,
當然包括我和我的妻子
including me and my wife, by the way,
沉迷於《單身漢》
are addicted to The Bachelor?
《單身漢》  美國選秀節目
好
Okay.
騙子
Liars.
騙子  數量絕對要比舉手的人多
Liars! I know there's way more of you out there than that.
說謊是一種罪過  各位
It's a sin to lie, people.
在教堂說謊更甚  所以
It's even a worse sin to lie in church, so...
好
Okay.
凱茜
Cathy?
想和你說幾句
I'mma pick on you for a second.
凱茜  我想知道
Cathy, I happen to know,
我在超市結賬的時候聽說
because I overheard it in a supermarket checkout line,
聽說你在看《天堂裡的單身漢》
that you watch Bachelor in Paradise.
《天堂裡的單身漢》  美國ABC電視台娛樂節目
誰還會到了天堂還只想著看《單身漢》
Now nobody watches just Bachelor in paradise.
不好意思  這就像是我去阿比家
I'm sorry, that's like saying I go to Arby's...
阿比家  美國快餐三明治連鎖餐廳
卻只點了一份沙拉
you know, just for the salads.
沒錯  我確實看
Yes, I do watch it.
好  和我想的一樣
Okay, that's what I thought.
我敢說你的丈夫  鮑勃  也看
And I bet that means that your husband, Bob, watches it too.
鮑勃  我懂  我懂
Bob, I get it. I get it.
首先  肯定是她強迫你看的  對嗎
At first, it was 'cause she forced you to do it, right?
你入迷了  現在你也有疑問了  是嗎
You got hooked. You got a problem now, right?
比如  安迪到底怎樣才能找到真愛
You're like, "How is Andy ever gonna find true love?" Right?
還記得上一季裡的胡安·巴布羅嗎
Remember this guy last season, Juan Pablo?
這個人
This guy.
你知道這傢伙最讓我生氣的是什麼嗎
You know what really ticked me off about this guy?
他不停地要女人們做出承諾
He kept asking these women to make a commitment,
日復一日
week after week.
但該他做出承諾的時候
But when it came time for him to make a commitment,
他害怕了  對嗎
he chickened out, right?
他不停地問  你願意接受我的玫瑰嗎
He kept saying, "Will you accept my rose?
你願意接受我的玫瑰嗎  你願意嗎
Will you accept my rose? Will you...?"
但當有人要求他付諸行動
But when someone asked him to get up to the plate...
他卻不敢去做
he couldn't find the courage to do it.
我很確定你們都知道我要說什麼
I'm pretty sure you guys all know where I'm going with this,
這是事實
but it's true.
一周又一周  祂為我們而來
Week after week. He's there for us.
而且  上帝也要求一輩子的承諾
And, yeah, God is asking for a lifetime commitment too.
但這是好消息  我確實覺得是好消息
But here's the good news, and I do mean the good news.
祂不只是給我們一朵玫瑰  對吧
He didn't just give us a rose, right?
祂把最珍貴的東西捨棄給了我們
He gave us the most valuable thing that He had to give.
祂的兒子
His son.
我想這意味著我們應該
And I think that means that we probably
也不應該食言而肥  對吧
shouldn't be commitment-phobes either, right?
好了  我們打開聖經
All right, let's open our Bibles.
路加福音
The Gospel of Luke.
你今晚要去看比賽嗎
You coming to the game tonight?
不了  我去不來  喬伊絲
No. I'm not gonna be able to make it, Joyce.
嘿  喬伊絲
Hey, Joyce!
-保拉  你好嗎  -很高興見到你
- Paula, how are you? - So good to see you.
-你也是  -謝謝
- You too. - Thank you.
-嗨  -嗨  你好嗎
- Hi. - Hi, how are you?
嗨  喬伊絲
Hi, Joyce.
你們這一天剩下時間都想幹嘛
Oh, what do you guys have on for the rest of the day?
約翰有一場籃球賽
Uh, well, John's got a basketball game.
是嗎  我見過約翰有時在這附近玩
Oh, yeah? I've seen John hoop it up a little bit around here.
這傢伙就是個野獸
This guy's a beast!
你覺得呢  J-Money
What do you say, J-Money?
來青年團嘛  就這周
Coming to Youth Group this week?
小菜雞  來吧
Weak sauce! Come on!
好吧  我會來的
All right, I'll come.
耶  這就對了  這孩子真是
Boom! There we go. This kid is so...
讓人沸騰
lit!
我一點不知道你在說什麼
I've no idea what you're going on about,
但我們得走了
but we have got to go.
-今天布道很好  牧師  -謝謝  布萊恩
- Nice sermon today, Pastor. - Thanks, Brian.
嘿  叫我傑森
Hey, uh, call me Jason.
傑森
Jason.
拿好球  約翰  拿好球
Take it, John, take it!
幹得好
Good job.
沖吧  雄鷹隊  加油
Let's go, Eagles! Let's go!
他們得防住另一隊
They gotta hold 'em.
加油啊  注意防守
Come on, defense!
加油  防守
Let's go, defense!
你得分散開
You need to spread it out!
就這樣  對  約翰  幹得漂亮
Here we go, yeah, John! Good job.
好了  現在  注意時間
Okay, now, look at the clock.
約翰  陣型
John, set up Eagle!
快點  約翰  擺好陣型
Come on, John! Set it up!
-回來  -雄鷹隊
- Get back! - Eagle!
約翰  空擋  把球傳給他
John, he's open! Pass it to him!
-雄鷹隊  -3
- Eagle! - Three!
-John  -2
- John! - Two!
One!
耶  耶  約翰
Yeah! Oh, yeah, John.
約翰·史密斯
John Smith!
這場打的不錯  但是下一次
That was a good game, but next time I call a play
你最好聽我的指揮  明白了沒
you better listen to me, you hear me?
好吧  去洗澡吧  打得不錯
All right, go wash up. Good game!
你從這裡弄來的
You got 'em from here?
是的
We do.
我們要在回家的路上吃披薩
We're gonna grab pizza on the way home.
真棒  謝謝你  辛迪
Great. Thank you, Cindy.
隨時可以  比賽不錯
Any time. Good game.
你也是
You too.
明天記得給你媽媽發短信告訴她
Text your mom tomorrow, and tell her
什麼時間上哪接你  好嗎
when and where to pick you up, okay?
拜託  別忘了
Please, don't forget.
我不會的
I won't.
這是一場精彩的比賽  孩子
It was a good game, son.
沒錯
Yeah.
祝你玩得愉快
Have a great time.
別做傻事
And, uh, don't do anything stupid.
好的  布萊恩
Okay, Brian.
愛你們
Love you, guys.
不好意思  這樣你都可以接受嗎
I'm sorry, you're okay with that?
這只是一個階段
It's just a phase.
他只是想引起關注
He's just trying to get a reaction.
叫你布萊恩  還有不跟媽媽擁抱再見嗎
By calling you Brian? Or not hugging his mother goodbye?
兩者都有一點
A little bit of both.
他只是需要一些空間
He just needs some space,
也許我們應該放鬆一點
and maybe we should loosen up a bit.
你不能做他的父親又做最好的朋友  布萊恩
Listen, you can't be his father and his best friend, Brian.
為什麼不呢
Why not?
因為這樣行不通
Because it doesn't work that way.
-我來了  我來了  -你想看這個漂移嗎
- I'm coming! I'm coming! - You want to see this drift?
-準備好了嗎  -是的
- Ready? - Yeah.
阿比只喜歡我的帖子
Abby just liked my post.
我是說  她是很酷但她不是莫莉
She's cool. I mean, she's no Molly, but,
莫莉  她搬到了德克薩斯州
Molly? She moved to Texas.
那又怎樣  她總是給我發短信
So? She texts me, like, all the time.
快到了
Almost there.
大笨蛋
Big dub!
-來玩吧  約翰  -稍等一下
- Come play, John. - In a minute.
好吧
All right.
你小時候真醜
Oh! You were an ugly baby.
那不是我  傻瓜  那是我爸爸
That's not me, fool. That's my dad.
我是另一個
I'm the other one.
我媽媽覺得很有趣  我倆長得一模一樣
My mom thinks it's funny 'cause we look exactly alike.
確實  而且你們都很醜
You do, and you're both ugly.
-嘿  小伙子們  -怎麼了  媽媽
- Hey, guys? - Yeah, Mom?
不要通宵  好嗎
Let's not stay up all night, okay?
晚安  裡格太太
Night, Mrs. Rieger.
晚安  孩子們
Good night, boys.
馬丁·路德·金紀念日
2015年1月19日
酷  走吧
Cool! Let's go!
就這裡  就這裡  就這裡
Right here. Right here. Right here.
上  上  上  等等
Go! Go! Go! Hold up!
傳過去
Pass it. Yeah.
那是給小孩子的
That's for little kids!
傳球
Pass.
嘿  快來  快來
Hey, get on this thing. Get on this thing.
等我  推我一下
Wait for me. Push me.
來  來  來  讓他轉起來
Go! Go! Go! Spin him! Spin him!
繼續  快一點
Keep going! Go faster!
可以了  可以了  快停下來
Okay! Okay! Stop it!
我頭暈  我頭暈  我頭暈
I'm dizzy! I'm dizzy! I'm dizzy!
嘿  夥計們  我們去湖邊看看吧
Hey, guys. Let's check out the lake!
哦  天哪
Oh, my God!
好  我們走吧
Okay, let's go.
看看這個
Check this out!
耶  沒事的  足夠厚了
Yeah, we're good. Plenty thick.
我們走吧
Let's go.
我還是好暈
I'm still dizzy!
快點  別做一個懦夫
Come on! Don't be a wuss!
是的  來吧  我們玩標籤吧
Yeah, come on! Let's play tag.
貼他
Tag him.
快點  別磨蹭
Come on! Hurry up!
貼了  你是了
Tag! You're it!
我們走
Let's go!
來吧
Come on!
走  走  走
Go, go, go!
冰球鬆了  過來
The puck is loose! Come here!
約翰拿到了
John's got it!
中了
Goal!
好了  說雄鷹  3
Okay, say, "Eagles." Three!
2  1
Two! One!
雄鷹
Eagles!
貼他  貼他
Tag him! Tag him!
我在盡力了  不
I'm on it. No!
哦  他滑倒了  抓住他
Oh, he's slipping! Get him!
不  耶
No! Yeah!
-不可能  不可能  -蹲下
- Yo! No way! No way! - Stay down. Yeah!
很滑的  夥計們  當心
Whoa! It's slippery, guys. Watch out.
我們抓到你了
We got you.
嘿  孩子們
Hey, boys!
從冰上下來
Get off the ice!
不安全
Not safe!
我們正在為奧運會訓練  先生
We're training for the Olympics, sir.
請不要扼殺我們的夢想
Please don't be a dream killer.
也許他是對的
Maybe he's right.
你聽到一條裂縫了嗎
Have you heard a single crack?
夥計們  現在  不然我給警察打電話
Guys? Now, or I'm calling the cops.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
我們只需要先抓住我們的朋友
We just need to catch our friend first.
什麼  不  嘿
What? No, hey!
抓住他  回到這裡
Get him! Get back here.
不  住手  哦  天哪
Not it. Stop! Oh, my God!
把他放倒  把他放倒
Pin him down. Pin him down.
別緊張  快點
Yo, easy! Come on!
嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey!
你抓到我了  行了吧
You got me, okay?
你哪兒也去不了  停下
You're not going anywhere. Yo, stop!
早上好  昨天晚上玩的開心嗎
要我接你的時候  給我發短信
知道了
什麼時候去接你
喬希  堅持住
Josh, hold on!
不行  我堅持不住了  我的手太冷了
I can't! I can't hold on. My hands are too cold.
太滑了  太滑了  堅持住  裡格
I'm slipping. I'm slipping. Hold on, Rieger, hold on!
我站不起來  盡力呼吸
I can't get up! Just breathe!
來  我來推你
Here. I'll push you out!
來  我抓住你了  堅持住
Here. I got you. Hold on!
約翰
John!
嘿  約翰
Hey, John!
約翰  抓住我的手
John! Grab my hand, John!
約翰  約翰
John! John!
使勁游  加油  約翰  約翰
Swim, come on! John! John!
他沉到底下了  我看不見他的臉了
He went under. I can't see his face!
-救命啊  -他去哪了
- Help! - Where'd he go?
使勁游  你可以的
Swim! You can do it.
約翰
John!
來人啊  救命啊
Please, someone help!
約翰
John!
誰來幫幫我們
Please, someone!
救命
Help!
911  有什麼緊急情況
9-1-1, what's your emergency?
三個男孩從冰上掉下去了
Three boys, they fell through the ice.
你們快點來幫忙
You gotta send help right now!
所有空閒消防車
All available trucks,
聖路易斯湖有一起溺水事件
we have a drowning event at Lake Saint Louis.
請報告你方地點  完畢
Call out locations please. Over.
動起來  快走
Move! Let's go!
11號車  我們在七分鐘車程處消防站
Truck 11, we're at the station seven minutes out.
我們車輛已配備水中救援設施  完畢
We're inbound with water rescue gear. Over.
他們在哪
Where are they?
就在下邊  那裡  三十碼外
Just down there. Right over there! Thirty yards out.
好
All right.
東面入口  離岸30碼
East entrance. Thirty yards off shore.
當地警方已經到達
Local police have arrived on scene.
一人已出水  一人在水中  一人在冰面下
One out, one in the water, one under the ice.
多久了
How long?
根據目擊者描述
Approximately five to seven minutes,
大概五至七分鐘
according to witnesses.
收到  告訴警長我們還有兩分鐘趕到
Copy. Tell Chief we're two minutes out.
救救我們
Help us!
-這裡的冰要碎了  -你退後  我去
- She's breaking under me. - Stay back! I'll go!
待在那  我們來救你們了
Stay there! We're coming to get you!
求你們幫幫我們  快點
Please help us. Hurry!
快點  求你們了
Hurry! Please!
幫幫我們
Please, help us.
我撐不下去了
I can't hold on much longer.
他還在水下
He's under the water.
我先救你的朋友  等一下再來救你
Let me get your friend. I'll get you next.
把手遞給我  把手遞給我
Give me your hand! Give me your hand!
來  我拉住你了
Come on, I got ya.
謝謝你
Thank you.
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
拿上鉤桿  方便拖撈湖底的人
Let's get the pike pole, so we can drag the bottom.
-我們還要更多  -我們還需要多少
- We need more! - How many do we need?
我瞭解這邊的湖
I know this area of the lake.
三米到三米半深
Ten, maybe 12 feet deep.
-拿三個來    -收到
- Grab three! - Got it.
-底下還有一個嗎  警長  -沒錯
- Still got one under, Chief? - Yeah.
氣罐和潛水營救裝置已經到達
But dive and retrieval with tanks are inbound.
裂縫正在擴大
The crack's widening.
我們得讓另外這孩子離水邊遠點
We've gotta get the other kid away from the edge.
-這孩子怎麼樣  -體溫低  但還有呼吸
- How's yours? - Hypothermic, but still breathing.
冰面正在開裂  當心點
The ice is giving way. Be careful!
我要救的那個在下邊多久了
How long's mine been under?
根據我們的信息至少有十分鐘了
At least ten minutes by our count!
求你們救救他
Please save him.
他在水下
He's under the water.
他掉到水下邊了  求求你們  他叫約翰
He went under the water. Please! His name is John.
-好的  好的  -求你們救救他
- It's okay. It's okay. - Please! Please save him.
聽我的指示  爬過來抓住這位警官的手
I want you to crawl over and grab this officer's hand.
我們會盡全力找到約翰
We're going to do everything we can to find John.
-過來吧  -求你們一定找到他
- Come on. - Please find him.
慢點進來  喬
Easy getting in, Joe.
我們不能再把他往下推了
We don't wanna push him farther under.
我們從後向前搜索
Let's work from back to front.
這片區域在擴大嗎  還是我的錯覺
Is the area widening, or is it just me?
確實在擴大
It's getting bigger.
大概三米深觸底
Bottom contact's about ten feet.
我們必須找到這孩子
We gotta find this kid.
好了
Ready.
多久了
What's the count?
十五分鐘
Fifteen minutes.
我們只能找他  救不了他了
It's gonna be a recovery, not a rescue.
嘿  醫護小隊
Hey, emt?
拿上背包
Get your backpack.
我還需要一個背包
I need another backpack.
往回走  往回走
Go back. Go back.
好像警長剛喊了一句"往回走"
Sounds like Chief just said, "Go back."
我沒聽到
I missed it.
他在說什麼
What's he talking about?
我連一米深都看不清  太模糊了
I can't see past three feet. It's way too murky.
我不想劃傷他
I don't wanna cut him.
湯米  如果他在那麼遠的冰下
Tommy, if he went under the ice back there,
就救不回來了
he's a goner.
最遠的邊緣掉到七米以外
The outmost edge drops off to 25 feet or more.
快點  約翰  讓我找到你
Come on, John. Be here.
我碰到什麼了
I got something.
是什麼
What is it?
是他嗎
Is it him?
湯米
Tommy?
別讓他掉下去  湯米
Don't lose him, Tommy.
-拉他起來  拉他起來  -我們找到他了
- Pull him up. Pull him up. - We got him.
我們找到他了
We got him!
我要抓不住了
I'm losing my grip.
我們找到他了
We got him!
救護隊  把繩子扔過來
Crew, throw the line!
繩子扔出  準備往回拉
Rope is out. Prepare for retrieval.
我抓著他呢
I got him.
拉
Pull!
開始拉
Here we go!
拉
Pull!
快點  繼續拉
Come on! Keep going!
他沒有脈搏了
He has no pulse.
開始胸外按壓
Start compressions.
快  快  快
Go! Go! Go!
二  三  四  五
Two! Three! Four! Five!
停
Stop!
拉  拉
Pull! Pull!
一  二  三  四  五
One! Two! Three! Four! Five...
九  十  十一  十二
Nine! Ten! Eleven! Twelve...
氧氣面罩
Ventilation tube.
一  二
One! Two!
挺住  約翰
Come on, John.
辛迪
Cindy!
我一直等你的電話呢
I've been expecting your call.
喬伊絲  發生了一起意外
Joyce, so there's been an accident.
孩子們在冰面上玩
Uh, the boys were out playing on the ice
他們掉下去了
and they fell through.
你現在得馬上趕到醫院
So you need to get to the hospital right now.
約翰在那邊  孩子們全都在那邊
They have John there. All the boys are there.
喂
Hey!
我剛買上你想要的那個調光開關
I'm just picking up that dimmer switch that you wanted.
布萊恩
Brian!
-約翰出事了  -喬伊絲
- John was in an accident. - Joyce.
孩子們掉到冰下邊去了
The boys fell through the ice!
喬伊絲  喬伊絲  慢點說
Joyce, Joyce. Slow down.
我現在往聖喬瑟夫西醫院趕
I'm going to St. Joseph West Hospital.
我們在那邊見好嗎
Can you please meet me there?
好  好  我們那邊見
Okay, okay. I'll meet you there.
喬伊絲  冷靜點
Joyce, calm down.
冷靜點
Calm down.
什麼情況
What do we know?
十四歲男性  無應答無脈搏
Fourteen-year-old male, unresponsive and pulseless.
他在冰面上玩  掉下去了
He was playing on the ice and fell through.
已注射了五百毫升
Five hundred cc bolus given.
他身體很冷
He's very cold to touch.
基斯  繼續胸外心臟按壓
Keith, take over CPR compressions.
給他注射生理鹽水
Let's bolus him, normal saline.
開始靜脈注射  按80磅體重的劑量注射
Run the IV wide open. We use a weight of 80 pounds.
準備注射腎上腺素
Prepare to give epinephrine.
腎上腺素注入
Epinephrine is in.
暫停按壓
Hold compressions.
沒有脈搏  身體還是冷的
No pulse. Still cold.
瞳孔固定且擴張  無應答
Pupils are fixed and dilated. No response.
繼續按壓
Resume compressions.
準備注射腎上腺素
Prepare to give epinephrine.
腎上腺素0.38毫克
Epinephrine 0.38 milligrams.
體內溫度三十一攝氏度
The temp is 88 degrees.
下一次脈搏檢查還有多久
How much long till the next pulse check?
三十秒
Thirty seconds.
求你了  上帝  求求你  上帝耶穌
Please, Lord. Please, Lord Jesus.
求求你
Please.
下次到時間時脈搏檢查
Check pulse at the next pulse check.
如果沒有脈搏  得用除顫儀了
If there is no pulse, we're gonna shock him.
得試試別的了  150焦耳除顫
Gotta try something. Shock at a 150 joules.
-準備除顫  -兩分鐘了
- Preparing to shock. - Two minutes.
沒有脈搏
No pulse.
大家  離手
Everyone, clear.
除顫
Shocking.
沒有脈搏
No pulse.
體表溫度多少
What's the outside temperature?
十度左右
Low 50s.
湖水的溫度沒有低到足夠
Lake water can't be cold enough
給他的心臟  或者他的大腦造成傷害
to have done his heart any good, or his brain for that matter.
體內溫度32攝氏度
Temp is up to 90 degrees.
-準備注射腎上腺素  -腎上腺素注入
Prepare to give epinephrine. Epinephrine is in.
腎上腺素  0.38毫克
Epinephrine, 0.38 milligrams.
想想  肯特  好好想想
Think, Kent. Think.
我們注射了多少腎上腺素了
How much epi have we given?
八劑量了  醫生
Eight doses, Doctor.
準備電擊
Prepare to shock.
兩分鐘了
Two minutes.
沒有脈搏
No pulse.
好吧  離手
All right. Everybody, clear.
除顫
Shocking.
沒有脈搏
No pulse.
體內溫度有37攝氏度了
Temp is up to 95 degrees.
他暖和起來了
He's warm.
已經有45分鐘了  醫生
Total time is 45 minutes, Doctor.
斯塔特醫生
Doctor Sutterer.
我們
There's...
There's, uh...
我們無能為力了
There's nothing more we can do.
我們現在就等他媽媽過來
We'll wait on his mother.
基斯  別停下來
Keith, keep going.
我不會的  頭兒
I'm not going anywhere, boss.
求你了  上帝  拜託了  主耶穌
Please, Lord. Please, Lord Jesus.
我是來看約翰·史密斯的
I'm here for John Smith.
好的
Okay.
您可以在那邊坐下
You can have a seat right over there.
我們在等他的父母過來
We're just waiting for his parents to arrive.
我是他的母親
I am his mother.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
請稍等
Just a moment.
她來了
She's here.
我要把她帶進來嗎
Should I bring her down?
我去吧
I'll go.
喬伊絲  我來了
Joyce, I'm here.
他們不讓我見他
They won't let me see him!
我的約翰就在裡面但他們不讓我見他
My John is in there and they will not let me see him!
這是違法的吧
Isn't that illegal?
我們耐心一點
We just need to be patient.
-喬伊絲·斯密斯  -是  我是喬伊絲
- Joyce Smith? - Yes? I'm Joyce.
你好  我是肯特·斯塔特醫生
Hi. I'm Doctor Kent Sutterer.
你的兒子  我們已經盡力了
We're doing everything we can for your son,
但約翰沒有反應
but John isn't responding.
這是什麼意思
What does that mean?
讓我帶你過去吧
Let me take you to him.
好了  各位
Okay, team.
基斯
Keith.
喬伊絲  我們就在外面待著
Joyce, we'll be right outside.
你可以慢慢跟他道別
Please, uh, take as long as you need to say goodbye.
什麼
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我不懂  我不
I don't understand. I don't,
不
No.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
不
No!
不  不  不  上帝啊
No, no, no. God.
求您了  耶穌  求您了
Please, Jesus, please.
求您了啊  耶穌
Please, Jesus.
我的約翰  我的約翰
My John. My John...
聖靈啊  我現在需要您啊
Holy Spirit, I need you now.
我現在真的很需要您啊
I need you now.
求您了  請不要帶走我的兒子
Please, please, don't take my son.
求您了  求您了啊
Please! Please!
請讓約翰活過來吧
Please bring life back into John.
求您了
Please!
求您了  上帝  拜託  拜託
Please, God! Please, please, please.
來吧  給約翰注入生命
Come, breathe life into John.
拜託了  上帝
Please, God...
求求您了  上帝
Please, God.
請您派您的聖靈來拯救我的兒子吧
Send your Holy Spirit to save my son!
-有脈搏了  -什麼
- We've got a pulse! - What?
什麼
What?
他有脈搏了
We've got a pulse!
我們有脈搏了  二級創傷
We've got a pulse! Trauma two.
通知呼吸科  我們需要呼吸機
Page Respiratory and let them know we need a ventilator.
-有脈搏嗎  -有
- You got a pulse? - Yes.
準備插管
Prepare intubation.
我去拿胃管  插管後隨時準備插入
I'll get the NG and be ready to insert it post-intubation.
喬伊絲
Joyce?
約翰在哪兒
Where's John?
喬伊絲
Joyce.
布萊恩
Oh, Brian.
-約翰怎麼樣了  -他
- How's John? - Well...
約翰有脈搏了  但很微弱
John's got a pulse, but it's weak.
我們正在盡可能的維持他的生命體征
Now, we're doing everything we can to stabilize him,
並且我們決定現在就把他
and we're airlifting him
轉移到市中心的卡迪納爾格倫農醫院
to Cardinal Glennon downtown right now.
他們那兒有最頂尖的溺水專家加勒特醫生
They've got the foremost expert in drowning, Doctor Garrett.
在我看來  他是約翰的唯一希望
Now, in my opinion, he's John's only chance.
空中管制中心  這裡是三三四空運機
ATC, this is Cardinal Glennon 3-3-4 airlift wing.
我會跟過去的  甜心
I'll follow you there, honey!
正在前往卡迪納爾格倫農兒童醫院
Go for CGCH.
現在申請飛行計劃
We're requesting a flight program now.
你們到二號台來
I have you coming in at pad two
有護送人員和創傷治療人員協助你們
with escort and trauma support staff to assist.
女士  您能坐飛機嗎
Ma'am, are you able to fly?
可以的  我沒事  沒事
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
你有點喘不過氣
You're hyperventilating.
我怕高怕得要死
I'm scared to death of heights.
您要是坐車過去可能會好點
I think it might be better if you traveled by car.
不行  我不會離開我兒子的
No, I'm not gonna leave my son!
好吧
Okay!
寶貝
Hey, babe!
你絕對會為我高興的  我正在慢跑
You'll be proud of me. I'm jogging off that...
約翰·史密斯掉進了一個冰湖裡
John Smith fell through a frozen lake!
等等  什麼
Wait, what?
他們正在用直升機把他送到卡迪納爾格倫農醫院
They're airlifting him to Cardinal Glennon.
行
Okay. Um...
我現在就過去
I'm on my way.
-你是約翰的母親對嗎  -是的
- You're John's mother, right? - Yes.
請跟我來  女士
I need you to come with me, ma'am.
加勒特醫生是約翰的主治醫師
Doctor Garrett will be the physician attending to John.
好的  好的
Okay. Okay.
等他穩定下來了  我們會立刻通知您
We'll come find you as soon as we get him situated.
好了  您先坐在這吧
Okay. You can have a seat right over there.
史密斯一家
Smith family.
他從聖約瑟夫乘直升機來的
He was helicoptered in from St. Joseph.
她到了  所以
Uh, she's here now, so...
一有消息我們就會通知您的
We'll let you know as soon as we hear something.
謝謝
Thank you.
現在不是好時機
It's really not a good time right now.
對  我知道  喬伊絲
Yeah, I know, Joyce.
這就是我來這兒的原因
That's why I'm here.
好吧  謝謝你能來
Well, thanks for coming.
我不會走的
Well, I'm not leaving.
至少不是現在
Not now, anyway.
你什麼意思
Excuse me?
聽著  喬伊絲  我知道你可能
Look, Joyce. I know you might not be
不太喜歡我的傳道方式
the biggest fan of how I preach,
亦或是我的髮型
or my haircut.
但我是約翰的牧師  也是你的牧師
But I'm John's pastor. And I'm your pastor.
我想  此時此刻
I think that means that right now,
我們應該先放下心裡的那些偏見
we gotta set aside our differences.
我們應該把精力放在約翰上  對麼
We gotta focus on John. Right?
布萊恩
Brian!
你能來真是太好了
Thank you for coming.
是的  醫生  我們已經調高滴速了
Yes, Doctor. We've increased the drip rate.
我是加勒特醫生
I'm Doctor Garrett.
很抱歉我們得在這種情況下認識
I'm sorry to be meeting under these circumstances.
你們的兒子還活著
Your son is alive,
但他的脈搏非常  非常虛弱
but his pulse is very, very weak.
約翰的大腦  也和他別的器官一樣
John's brain, like his organs,
在進行心臟復甦前
was deprived of oxygen for at least 20 minutes
缺氧缺了至少20分鐘
before CPR was administered.
他的傷可以說是災難性的了
His injuries are catastrophic.
除了基本的大腦功能
Beyond rudimentary brain function...
我從來沒碰到過像約翰這樣的情況
I've never seen a case like John's.
實際上  他的損傷程度已經很深了
The fact that he's made it this far...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
很深是什麼意思
"This far"?
醫生
Doctor?
即使約翰恢復意識了
If John ever regained consciousness...
他也會受到嚴重的神經損傷
he'd be severely neurologically impaired.
對不起  史密斯夫婦
I'm sorry, Mr. And Mrs. Smith.
但我覺得約翰可能熬不過今晚了
But I don't believe John will survive the night.
如果你們還想打電話給別的親戚朋友
If you have family and friends
讓他們來看看約翰的話
that you want to call to come to see John,
現在就是時候了
now would be the time to do it.
加勒特醫生  別人告訴我你是最優秀的
I've been told that you are the best, Doctor Garrett.
我只是比較在行而已  女士
I'm an expert in my field, ma'am.
不  你是最優秀的那個
No, you're the best.
其實  應該說是世界聞名
World renowned, in fact.
還是說  我聽到的都是謠傳嗎
Or was I misinformed?
不  你沒有
No, you were not.
我知道您不認識我兒子
I know that you don't know my son,
但我的約翰是個永不言棄的戰士
but my John is a fighter and he doesn't give up.
所以我希望您可以為了約翰
So, I need you to go
而成為最優秀的那個
and be the best for John.
我別無所求
Nothing less.
然後將剩下的一切交給上帝就好了
And you just let God do the rest.
好吧
Okay.
這真的事一瞬間的事
It's been real touch and go.
不能再告訴我們多些內容嗎
Can't tell us anything more?
他們來了
Here they are.
嘿  梅麗莎
Hey, Melissa.
我真的很遺憾  甜心
I'm so sorry, hon.
我們一看到新聞就趕過來了
We headed over the minute we heard the news.
他們有說約翰怎麼樣了嗎
What are they saying about John?
這麼說吧  我不會把剛剛
Well, I'm not gonna say
醫生想說的結果告訴你們的
what the doctor just tried to tell me,
因為我不接受他的話
because I refuse to accept it.
約翰會度過這一切的
Because John is gonna get through this.
喬伊絲
Joyce,
關於約翰能不能活下來
I think you need to be honest with yourself
我想你還是不要自欺欺人的好
about John's chances.
我沒在自欺欺人
I am being honest about his chances.
好吧  我要回那兒去了
You know, I'm gonna get back.
他們只允許兩個人呆在病房裡
They're only allowing two people in the room at a time.
布萊恩
Brian?
布萊恩  我們走吧
Brian. Let's go.
你和傑森先去吧
Oh, you and Jason go.
我等會再去
I'll hang back.
-你確定嗎  -是的  謝謝了
- Are you sure? - Yes, thank you.
他們怎麼樣了
How are the boys?
兩個喬希都已經在幾個小時前出院了
Well, the two Joshes were released a few hours ago.
他們體溫過低了  但會好起來的
They suffered some hypothermia, but they're gonna be fine.
那約翰呢
And John?
約翰的處境很危險  寶貝
John is in a very tough spot, honey.
但他還有脈搏
But he's got a pulse,
這已經超出很多人的預料了
which is a lot more than anyone thought possible.
媽媽說這大概是個奇跡
Mom said it was some kinda miracle.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah...
我還是不知道怎麼形容這件事
I still don't know quite how to put it into words.
他的媽媽很感性
His mom, she was so emotional,
她當時一直在祈禱
she was praying and...
我還是不敢相信  那孩子就
I still can't believe it. He just...
他就活過來了
He just came back to life.
所以  約翰會好起來的對吧
So, John's gonna be okay?
你爸爸今天已經很累了  寶貝
Your dad's had a long day, honey.
我知道  可是
I know, but...
我該怎麼告訴班裡的同學呢
what do I tell the kids in my class?
其實  親愛的
Well, honey,
誰都無法肯定到底發生了什麼
the truth is nobody knows for sure.
那約翰有可能在這這周內回學校嗎
Is there a chance John will be back to school this week?
不  親愛的
No, honey.
他要一直待在卡迪納爾格倫農醫院直到
He's gonna be at Cardinal Glennon until...
親愛的  我覺得約翰撐不了多久了
Honey, I don't think John is gonna live much longer.
但你說他活過來了啊
But you said he came back to life.
我知道
I know.
目前是這樣  親愛的
For now, honey.
對  只是目前而已
Yeah, for now.
但這件事是
But it's...
它很複雜
You know, it's complicated.
我從醫院得到了最新消息
I got an update from the hospital.
他們
They, um...
他們覺得那個男孩撐不過今晚了
They don't expect that boy to make it through the night.
那是今天的事  夥計
That was something today, bud.
你做了什麼
What you did?
如果局長沒有讓我們原路返回
Well, if Chief hadn't asked us to double back,
一直在最開始的地方肯定找不到他
never would've found him in the first place.
你說啥
Say what?
如果你沒有喊我們往回走
If you hadn't yelled for us to go back.
我還以為你當時瘋了
I thought you were nuts.
我沒有喊你倆啊
I didn't yell at you guys.
我當時在努力地幫另外那兩個男孩
No, I was knee-deep in trying to help those other boys
保證他們的手指腳趾不會凍壞
not lose their fingers and toes.
我壓根沒聽到
I never heard it.
你是那個把他撈起來的人  湯米
You're the one who found him, Tommy.
我是有幫你把他拉出來  但是
I helped you fish him out, but...
剩下的功勞都是你的
the rest was all you.
我當時聽到有人喊"往回走"
I heard a voice say "Go back."
那是誰喊的
So who was it?
不是我
It wasn't me.
你在跟我開玩笑吧  局長
You're messing with me, Chief.
沒有
No.
我只是坐在這
I'm just sitting here listening to you
聽你裝謙虛而已
trying to sound humble,
這可真不像你
which really doesn't suit you.
我今天見證了一件非常了不起的事情
What I witnessed today was something quite remarkable.
甚至可以說是一個奇跡
Some might even call it a miracle,
這也是我把它寫下來了的原因
which is why I'm writing.
這樣無論發生什麼
So that no matter what happens,
我們都能銘記今天所看到的東西
we will remember what we witnessed today.
為約翰祈禱
J·謝拉女士
2015年1月20日
約翰出事18小時後
我的約翰撐過這個晚上了
My John made it through the night.
那是  他當然能啦
Yeah, of course he did.
他可是個小戰士
He's a fighter.
我專門問了布萊恩
Oh, I did some investigative research with Brian.
兩勺奶  一勺糖
Two creams, one sugar.
謝謝
Thank you.
也謝謝你昨晚留下來  傑森
And thank you for staying the night, Jason.
怎麼了
What?
這是你第一次叫我傑森
That's the first time you've ever called me Jason.
抱歉  我一直對你態度很惡劣
I'm sorry. I've been awful to you.
不  得了吧  這是什麼話
No! Come on. What are you talking about?
誰會不喜歡一份唱詩班的舉報信呢
Who doesn't love a typed, two-page, single-spaced,
尤其還是單倍行距雙面打印的
anonymous complaint letter about the worship band?
搞說唱是真的有點過分了
The rapper was a bit much.
好吧
Okay.
我是聽著讚美詩長大的
I grew up on hymns.
等等  你怎麼知道是我寫的
Wait, how'd you know it was me?
我不知道啊
I didn't.
所以
So...
聽著  喬伊絲
Listen, Joyce.
我換了教堂的音樂風格
The only reason I switched up the music at church
是因為我想
is because I will do
盡我所能地
absolutely everything and anything,
去鼓勵年輕人能夠來教堂
to get young people psyched to go to church.
像約翰那樣的小孩
Kids like John, it's just...
他們需要更多的一些關注  你懂吧
They need a little more cowbell, you know?
對  我明白你意思
Yeah, I see your point.
保拉肯定很討厭我
Oh, Paula must hate me.
不  不會  她覺得你是充滿活力的人
No. No, she thinks you're very... spirited.
要不你回家看看你的家人吧
Why don't you go home and see your family?
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
當然  當然了  你可以回去
Yes, yes, of course.
早上好  各位
Good morning, everyone.
早上好
Morning.
有什麼需要就給我打電話
Uh, call me if you need me for anything.
-我很快就回來  -好  謝謝
- I'll be back real soon. - All right. Thanks.
我剛從溫迪那裡拿到了最新的檢查結果
Uh, I just got the update from Wendy.
我不知道約翰是怎麼撐過昨晚的
I don't know how John made it through the night.
但我很高興我之前的判斷是錯的
But I'm glad I was wrong.
我有點擔心他會出現腦水腫
I am worried about cerebral edema.
就像身體的其他部位一樣
Like the rest of John's body,
他的大腦可能會出現水腫
his brain's going to wanna swell.
我會讓他持續保持昏迷狀態
I'm gonna keep John in an induced coma,
這樣他的身體才有可能恢復過來
give his body a chance to reverse course.
我們今天還會給他做很多檢查  好吧
And we're gonna run a lot of tests today. Okay?
最好能盡快檢查出一些
It's imperative that we see some kind of real proof
約翰大腦活動的特徵
of brain activity in John.
好
Yeah.
儘管如此  還是有很長的路要走
At best, we have a long road ahead.
我也不想騙你
And I'm not gonna lie to you.
現在一切還不好說
We're in uncharted territory.
一個來自聖查爾斯的十四歲男孩
A fourteen-year-old St. Charles boy,
從冰面落入了聖路易斯湖
who spent 15 minutes trapped underwater,
在水下被困整整15分鐘
after falling through the ice on Lake Saint Louis,
目前仍在與死神鬥爭
is continuing to fight for his life today.
星期一  第一批救援者救起約翰·史密斯時
On Monday, after first responders,
他已經無脈搏無應答反應
recovered John Smith's unresponsive and pulseless body,
隨後他被送到了聖喬瑟夫西醫院
John was transported to St. Joseph West Hospital,
急救小組持續為他做了
where the trauma team continued life-saving CPR efforts,
長達45分鐘的心肺復甦
for an additional 45 minutes.
他整整一小時都沒有出現生命體征
It was then, that after an hour
就在那時
with no signs of life,
約翰的母親  喬伊絲為他祈禱了一會
John's mother, Joyce, prayed.
緊接著  約翰的脈搏就重新出現了
And John got a pulse.
他立即被直升機轉送到了
John was then quickly airlifted here
卡迪納爾格倫農醫院醫院
to Cardinal Glennon Hospital,
在這裡我們得知  加勒特醫生和他的團隊
where we're told that Doctor Garrett and his team
也在晝夜不停地工作
are working around the clock,
盡力去挽救約翰·史密斯的生命
in an effort to save John Smith's life.
這是凱·奎因在
This is Kay Quinn reporting live
卡迪納爾格倫農醫院醫院為您現場報道
from Cardinal Glennon Hospital.
傑森在哪
Where's Jason?
其它方面新聞  昨天抗議者們
And in other news, yesterday, protesters...
我讓他回家了
I sent him home.
今天早上加勒特醫生來了  可你錯過了
You missed Doctor Garrett this morning.
不  他來找我了
No, he came and found me.
布萊恩  你昨晚沒回來
Brian, you didn't come back last night.
我不忍心看著他這樣
I can't see him like this.
在這個房間裡我根本待不下去
I can't be in this room...
看著他這樣
seeing him in this state.
對不起
I'm sorry.
有任何需要的話
If you need anything,
可以到走廊那找我
I'll just be right down the hall.
我不會離開的
I'm not leaving.
好吧
Okay.
梅麗莎覺得每個人都只是在
Melissa thinks that everyone...
等著看約翰死
is just waiting for John to die.
根本就是
That it's just...
他們覺得他只是垂死掙扎得比較久而已
It's just taking longer than they expected.
-那你怎麼想的  -我很抱歉  但是
- What do you think? - I'm sorry but...
我覺得她可能是對的
I think she's right.
所有人是這麼想的  除了
I can see it in their face and in everyone's face except...
我嗎
Mine?
我很確信上帝能讓我們的兒子痊癒
I believe God can heal our son completely.
我知道
I know you do.
我知道你相信
你昨晚為什麼要在醫院裡過夜啊
Why did you have to sleep at the hospital?
這麼說吧
Well...
你還記得我告訴過你
Remember how I told you
"牧師"也被叫做"牧羊人"嗎
another word for "pastor" can be "shepherd"?
牧羊人就是照看羊群的  對麼
Well, shepherds look after their sheep, right?
你總是跟媽媽說教堂裡的人像羊一樣
Is that why you always tell Mom
是因為這個嗎
the people at church are acting like sheep?
咱們還是別說這個了
Let's try not to repeat that.
不是啦  是約翰就像一頭受傷的羊
No, uh, John's like a sheep that's been injured.
我下面說的都是事實哦
And this is a real thing,
有時這種情況的確是會發生的
this really happens sometimes.
當一個牧羊人在他的牧場裡
Sometimes when a shepherd finds a sheep
發現了一隻受傷的羊時
that's been injured in his pasture,
他會把它舉起來
he'll actually pick him up,
把它放到自己的脖子上
and he'll carry him around his neck.
為什麼
Why?
這樣那隻羊就能聽到他的心跳聲  對吧
Well, so that the sheep can hear his heartbeat, right?
他們之間就會因此出現一種羈絆了
And the two can form a bond.
所以你是要把約翰放到你的脖子上嗎
So you're gonna carry John around your neck?
呃  不完全是
Well, not literally.
我想我自己扼殺了這個比喻
I think I'm butchering this metaphor.
孩子們  你們爸爸要去醫院了
You guys, your dad is going to the hospital
陪在約翰的旁邊
to be by John's side.
這樣一來他就能聽到你爸爸的聲音
That way he can hear your dad's voice
並且知道你們的爸爸愛他
and know that your dad loves him.
因為這是牧師們應該做的
'Cause that is what pastors do.
他們愛他們的教眾
They love their people.
為什麼你不能直接說出來呢
Why didn't you just say that?
就是啊
Like, yeah.
我不知道  不知道怎麼說
I have no idea. I don't know.
你們倆應該刷牙去了
Why don't you go brush your teeth?
我覺得你們媽媽應該是個很合格的牧師
I think your mom should be the pastor, huh?
是的
Yup.
嘿  嘿  嘿  你們的盤子
Hey, hey, hey! Dishes?
我知道  對你們有點凶
Oh, I know. Ooh, so rough.
謝謝你們
Thank you!
怎麼了
Hey. What?
如果約翰死了
If John dies...
這件事會把她擊垮的
I mean, it's gonna destroy her.
她一直堅信他會活下來
She believes without a doubt that he'll survive.
湯米
Tommy.
你還好嗎
How you doing?
你想說什麼  頭兒
What's on your mind, Chief?
大家都認為
The guys think that, uh...
可能你對於那個孩子發生的一切
maybe you're still a little shook up
心裡還感到一些震驚
about what happened to the boy.
我知道我聽到了什麼
I know what I heard.
我相信你
I believe you.
那個湖遠不止幾英尺深
A few feet over...
大概有7米或更深 對嗎
That lake is, like, 25 feet deep or more, right?
是的
Yeah.
像我們那麼快找到他  可能嗎
To find him like we did, that fast?
百萬分之一
Million to one,
最好的情況下
best case.
你曾經經歷過那樣的事情嗎
Anything like that ever happen to you?
沒有
No.
好吧
Well...
我是這樣想的
The way I figure it,
只有兩種情況中的一個
it's either one of two things.
要麼是我瘋了
Either I'm nuts...
或者是上帝在和你說話
Or God's talking to you.
正是
Exactly.
不管哪種情況
In which case...
我都有一個很大的個人問題
I got a big personal problem.
什麼問題
What's that?
我不信上帝
I don't believe in God.
喬伊絲認為
Joyce thinks that John
約翰會好好的走出這家醫院
is gonna walk out of this hospital.
你是怎麼想的
What do you think?
我有些懷疑
I have my doubts,
如果你是在問這個的話
if that's what you're asking.
有人這麼說
That being said...
我認為是有可能的
I think it's possible.
我調查了很多溺水案例
I've been researching drowning cases,
有幾百例
hundreds of them.
像約翰那種情況的沒有一個活下來
No one in John's situation has ever survived.
我相信上帝
I believe in God.
但是像這樣的事  結局也許只能這樣了
But maybe that only goes so far with something like this.
老實跟你說
I'm gonna be honest with you.
我也不清楚上帝會對約翰做什麼
I have no idea what God will do with John.
我的意思是  我不知道
I mean, I have no idea.
我現在能做的就是一直陪在
All that I know is that I'm supposed to walk
你和喬伊絲的身邊
alongside you and Joyce right now.
現在最好的情況
Best case scenario...
就是我的兒子能夠活下來但是大腦嚴重受損
is that my son leaves here severely brain-damaged.
你能接受嗎
Could you handle that?
謝謝你  醫生
Thank you, Doctor.
我認為我們應該把注意力
I just think we should be focused
集中在還有希望的病人身上  不是嗎
on the patients we can actually help. Right?
這不是你我所能決定的  要聽加勒特醫生
That isn't your call or mine. It's Doctor Garrett's.
病人目前的這種情況
It is neurologically impossible
在神經學角度來說  是不可能恢復的
for the patient to change course at this point.
話雖如此
Be that as it may,
但我們的工作是滿足病人的需求
our job is to meet the needs of the patient,
直到加勒特醫生改變治療方案
until Doctor Garrett changes course
或者病人逝去
or the patient expires.
但是腦血管掃瞄顯示
But the cerebral blood flow scan
已經完全沒有
shows complete absence of...
病人的名字叫約翰
The patient's name is John.
約翰·史密斯
John Smith.
你好  我是盧盧醫生
Hello, I'm Doctor Lulu.
好
Yeah.
我和同事剛才只是在討論你兒子的病情
My colleagues and I were just discussing your son's case.
我聽到你們討論的內容了
Oh, I heard what you were discussing.
我們以為只有我們在這
We thought we were alone.
你當然這麼想
Of course you did.
但是我在這
But I'm here,
而且我的兒子現在就在你們面前
and my son is right in front of you.
他也能聽到你們談的  不管你們信不信
And my son can hear you whether you believe it or not.
所以從現在開始
So from now on,
我不想聽到任何人
I don't want anybody
說任何關於他病情的負面猜測
saying anything negative about his prognosis
在這個房間裡
in this room.
我們都要說約翰能夠倖存下來
We will all speak life over John.
我說的你聽懂了嗎
Do I make myself clear?
史密斯女士  我們真的不是故意讓你難過
Mrs. Smith, we really didn't mean to upset you.
我說  我說的話你聽懂了嗎
I said, do I make myself clear?
是的
Yes.
很好
Great.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
不好
No.
說實話  我的血糖很高
If I'm honest, my sugars are sky high,
而且頭還很痛
and I have a pounding headache.
好吧  這很糟糕
Okay, that's not good.
是的
Yeah.
我得回家拿我的胰島素  還有
I need to go home and get my insulin and I...
去吧
Go.
這交給布萊恩和我就行了
Look, Brian and I got this.
約翰的情況也穩定下來了
John's in stable condition.
也許你真的該休息一下了
Maybe you can actually get some rest.
好吧
Okay.
薩米
Sammy!
我想死你了
I've missed you.
你一定餓壞了吧
Oh, you must be starved.
我給你找點吃的
Let's get you something.
薩米已經餵過兩次也溜過了
還給它準備了一周的食物
冰箱裡還有些肉卷
愛你  讀書俱樂部
嗨
Hey.
他情況很穩定
He's stable.
沒有變化
No real changes.
我
I, um...
我把你的喬丹鞋帶來了
I brought your Jordans with me.
我知道你不允許別人碰它們
I know no one's allowed to touch them.
但是我就是覺得這樣可能
But I just thought that maybe...
我實在等不急想再次看到你
I can't wait to see you
投籃的樣子和你在球場上奔跑的身影
shoot those baskets and run up and down the court again.
你是我的驕傲和快樂 約翰
You are my pride and joy, John.
你聽到你媽媽叫你了嗎
Do you hear your mother?
而且我很愛你
And I love you to the moon.
不許你忘記它
And don't you forget it.
約翰
John?
他剛才握了一下我的手
He just squeezed my hand!
什麼
What?
真的嗎
Seriously?
是的  我很確定
Yes, absolutely.
約翰  再做一次  再握一下我的手
John, can you do it again? Can you squeeze my hand?
問他一些事情
Um, ask him something.
嗯  好
Uh, okay. Um...
約翰  如果你覺得邁克爾·喬丹是
John, squeeze my hand if...
最偉大的運動員  你就再握一下我的手
Michael Jordan is the best player of all time.
給傑森牧師看一看
Show Pastor Jason a thing or two.
我不知道
I don't know.
勒布朗也很棒啊
LeBron is pretty amazing.
我不知道  我不認為他是最好的  媽媽
I don't know, I don't think he can do it, Mom.
抓住他的另外一隻手
Grab his other hand.
親愛的  握一下我的手代表喬丹
Honey, squeeze my hand for Jordan
握傑森的手代表勒布朗  好嗎  寶貝
and Jason's for LeBron, okay, baby?
振作起來  老兄  你可以的
Come on, buddy, you got this.
有史以來最偉大的運動員  兒子
The best player of all time, son.
快點
Come on.
-太棒了  -我看到了
- Yeah! - I saw it!
約翰  誰創造了六次NBA冠軍的記錄
Um, John, who was it who got a record six NBA titles?
真的
Yeah!
我感覺到了  約翰
I feel you, John!
告訴我是誰跳到了邁阿密的後面成了第二
And who was it who hopped down to Miami for a second,
為了得到那枚戒指把粉絲們都得罪了
crushing his fans to get that ring?
他能聽到我們
He can hear us!
他握了我的手  喬伊絲  他握了我的手
He squeezed my hand. Joyce! He squeezed my hand.
天吶  我們要去告訴醫生
Oh, my God. We have to tell the doctors.
當然他媽的要了
Oh, hell yeah!
對不起
I'm sorry.
我有些激動了
I get pumped.
我去了
I'm going!
這位是加勒特醫生  約翰
It's Doctor Garrett, John.
你媽媽告訴我你能夠聽到我們說話
Your mom tells me that you can hear us.
是真的嗎
Is that true?
告訴醫生  約翰
Tell the doctor, John.
有史以來最好的運動員
Greatest player of all time.
握住我的手代表喬丹
Squeeze my hand for Jordan,
醫生的手代表勒布朗  好嗎 寶貝
and the doctor's for LeBron. Okay, baby?
不用握很大力
Doesn't have to be a hard squeeze.
只是讓我們知道你在聽  約翰
Just let us know you're there, John.
誰贏得了六次NBA的冠軍  老兄
Who won those six NBA titles, buddy?
我的手代表喬丹
My hand for Jordan.
醫生的手代表勒布朗  好嗎  寶貝
The doctor's hand for LeBron. Okay, baby?
你可以的
You got this.
約翰  我剛使勁握了你手一下
I just squeezed your hand, John.
你想握回來嗎
You wanna just squeeze mine right back?
別亂想  偶爾肌肉抽搐很正常
Phantom or, uh, random muscle tics are normal.
這不是偶然
It wasn't random.
對  他在回應我們
No, he was answering us.
表面看起來似乎如此
I know it can seem like that.
嗨  姑娘們
Hey, girls.
-J女士  你好  -謝謝你能來
- Hi, Mrs. J. - Thanks for coming.
-嗨  -嗨  謝謝你能來
- Hi. - Hi. Thanks for coming.
裡格  喬希
Rieger, Josh,
過來我們擁抱一下
get your butts over here and give me a hug.
聽著  看到你們沒事我很高興
Listen, I'm so glad you boys are okay.
我太抱歉了 史密斯女士
I'm so sorry, Mrs. Smith.
約翰躺在這都是我們的錯
It's our fault that John is in here.
不是的
No.
所以現在重要的是你們在這支持著約翰
So what matters now is that you're here to support John.
他是我跟他爸爸的全部
It means the world to his dad and me.
所以  很感謝你們
So thank you.
我們帶來了大家寫給約翰的祝福卡
We brought cards that, um... people made for John.
這
This is...
真是太棒了  謝謝你們
It's really wonderful. Thank you.
你能先拿一下嗎
Could you hold these a sec?
小伙子們  麻煩讓一下
Excuse me, boys.
謝謝你們
Thank you.
我不知道該說點什麼
There's no words.
聽著
Listen.
-我很抱歉  -別再說了
-  I'm so sorry. -  Not another word.
辛迪  這不怪你
Cindy, it's not your fault.
對不起
Sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我再也不會讓他當替補了
What I wouldn't give to bench that boy right now.
你看到我們為約翰製作的臉書主頁了嗎
Did you see the Facebook page that we made for John?
-還沒呢 -成了熱門話題
- No. - It's gone viral.
姑娘們
Oh, girls...
這太
This is so...
這太棒了  看
Oh, this is so wonderful! Wow! Look at...
這些祝福者還有
these prayers and,
我們會一直支持你  親愛的
We came to be supportive, honey,
這沒我們什麼事了
and there's nothing left for us to do here.
所以不要待在這了
So we need to not overstay our welcome.
-我想再呆在這會  -我們得走了
- I wanna stay longer! - We need to go. Okay?
姑娘們  我們得接受現實
Girls, look, we need to be prepared for the fact,
這次約翰可能挺不過去了
that John is probably not going to make it. Okay?
我真覺得你不會想在這看到這個的
I really don't think you wanna be here for that.
-媽媽  -我知道我不會
- Mom! - I know I don't.
J女士  你還好嗎
Mrs. J, are you okay?
還好
Yeah.
請大家聽我講好嗎
Can I have your attention?
就在大廳那邊
Just down that hall,
你們知道約翰為自己生命奮力拚搏嗎
do you know that John is fighting for his life?
知道嗎
Okay?
所以在這個房間裡
And so in this room,
請不要有任何消極的言論
there is no negative talk of any kind!
一句都不要有
Nothing!
行嗎
Okay?
謝謝大家
Thank you.
都是假的
Unreal.
-你還好嗎  -遠離他們
- You okay? - Far from it!
這些神經兮兮的人
The nerve of these people!
我們得談一談
Let's talk.
怎麼了
What's up?
我很擔心你  我知道你很生氣
I'm worried about you. I know you're angry.
對對  你說得對  我很生氣
Yeah. Yeah, you're right, I am.
那個房間裡的人不是你的敵人
The people in that room are not your enemy,
即便他們說了些不該說的話
even if they don't say exactly the right thing.
聽著  我同意你剛才在那所說的話
Look, I support what you said out there.
但是你對他們說話的方式  我
But the way you've spoken to some of the staff, I just...
怎麼了  布萊恩  說啊
What, Brian? Say it.
我覺得你得對他們友好一點
I need you to show them some... kindness
或者禮貌一點
or decency.
我在為我兒子的生命抗爭
I'm fighting for my son's life!
所有人都是
We all are!
所有人都在盡其所能挑戰不可能
Everybody is doing their best in an impossible situation.
如果不是為了我  我們兒子早就死了
If it wasn't for me, our son wouldn't be alive right now!
喬伊絲
Joyce.
你是我妻子  我愛你
You're my wife. I love you.
但無論發生什麼
But whatever happens,
我希望你都不要做出令自己後悔的事
I don't want you to regret how you acted here.
在我內心深處
In my heart of hearts,
我知道你也不想
I know that you don't want that either.
對他們那樣也救不了兒子
Grinding people into the ground isn't gonna save our son.
我求求你記住自己的身份
I am begging you to remember who you are.
就算不為我
If not for me,
也為約翰著想
for John.
2015年1月21日
約翰出事42小時後
醒醒
Wake up.
親愛的  該醒醒了
Honey, it's time to wake up.
喬伊絲  快醒醒
Joyce, wake up!
我妻子有糖尿病  她昏過去了
My wife is diabetic. I can't wake her!
叫輛救護車  我們快走
Okay. Call for a crash cart, let's go!
我需要幫助
Somebody give me a hand!
我這會兒好多了
I'm fine now.
昨晚可能吃了過量胰島素
I think I just took too much of my insulin last night.
你陷入了糖尿病昏迷
You slipped into a diabetic coma.
醫生  她的血糖升到了70
Her blood sugar is up to 70, Doctor.
謝謝你  護士
Thank you, Nurse.
看到了吧  我很好
See? I'm fine.
喬伊絲  你夠了
Joyce, you coded!
我得見約翰
I need to see John.
你至少得休息8小時
You need to rest for at least eight hours.
我想跟我兒子待在一起
I want to be with my son.
我不是在徵求你的意見  喬伊絲
I'm not asking, Joyce.
你患有1型糖尿病
You have Type 1 diabetes.
你由於情緒激動導致脫水
You're dehydrated, emotionally fried,
而且你好幾天沒睡覺了
and you haven't slept for days.
你為了約翰也得歇一會
I need you here for the long haul for John.
8小時不可能  最多3小時
Three hours, not eight. Best and final.
喬伊絲五小時內  不要讓我看到你去那
Joyce, I catch you in that room in less than five hours,
否則我會強制讓你離開醫院的
I'll have you involuntarily committed and taken across the street.
-你不會的  -他會的  我同意了
- You wouldn't. - He would, with my blessing!
喬伊絲  五個小時
Five hours, Joyce.
算好時間
Make 'em count.
現在真不是個好時機
It's really not a good time right now.
喬伊絲  我知道
Yeah, I know, Joyce.
所以我才來這兒
That's why I'm here.
說一下你對我的看法
What you must think of me.
你知道嗎
You know what?
我覺得你是最兇猛的熊媽媽
I think you are the fiercest mama bear
沒人比得上你
that I've ever known.
約翰怎麼樣了
How is John?
他情況很穩定
He's stable.
在我18歲時
So when I was 18,
我把我的第一個兒子送養了
I gave my first son up for adoption.
我還沒準備好養他
I wasn't ready,
我自己的生活也是一團糟
and my life was such a mess.
我永遠都不會原諒自己
I've never forgiven myself.
我放不下
I can't let it go.
我回不到過去也無法彌補
I can't go back. I can't fix it.
所以我告訴約翰怎麼花他的零用錢
So I tell John how to spend his allowance.
布萊恩應該系什麼樣的領帶
Brian what tie he should wear.
我堅持把我們的狗命名為薩米
I insisted on naming our dog "Sammy" for crying out loud.
約翰和布萊恩想叫它尤達
John and Brian wanted "Yoda."
這名字聽起來太蠢了
It's a pretty stupid name.
謝謝你
Thank you.
還有你  我還是想幫你修頭髮
Oh, and you, I still wanna fix your hair.
我一生中一直在
My whole life, I have not stopped
試圖控制結果
trying to control the outcome.
但這不是我能控制的  對嗎
I can't control this, can I?
喬伊絲  你為什麼不全然交給上帝呢
Joyce, why don't you let God handle it?
看來你又被允許上樓了
Well, looks like you're allowed back upstairs again.
是啊
Yeah.
如果你不介意的話  我要
Um, if you don't mind, I'm just gonna...
出去喘口氣
get a breath of fresh air outside.
行  我跟他們說
Okay, I'll tell everyone.
好的
Okay.
我知道您愛約翰
And I know that You love John,
就像我愛他一樣
just as much as I do.
甚至比我更愛
Maybe more.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我是個
I am a...
我是個心碎的
I am a broken,
絕望的
desperate,
但內心很驕傲的女人
woman full of pride.
但是我明白
But I get it.
我必須得放手了
I have to let him go.
我知道您愛我
I know You love me.
不管您為約翰  布萊恩  還有我自己
Whatever You have,
有什麼樣的安排
for John, for Brian, for me,
我認輸  認輸
I surrender. I surrender.
布萊恩  一切還好嗎
Brian, is everything okay?
不太好
I don't think so.
約翰現在高燒40度
John's fever just hit 104.
異丙酚  廣泛應用於臨床各科麻醉及重症病人鎮靜
約翰已經注射了整整兩天的異丙酚
Now, John's had two full days of propofol.
但這種藥最多只能連續使用24小時
And it's only meant to be taken at most for 24 hours.
我想這就是他發燒的原因
I think that's why his fever's spiking.
是你說需要用異丙酚
You said the propofol was needed
讓約翰保持持續昏迷
to keep John in an induced coma.
沒錯
That's right.
我們別無選擇  只能讓他保持深度昏迷
We had no other choice but to keep him deeply sedated.
我對這場高燒的擔憂
My concern now, with this raging fever,
是異丙酚
is that the propofol
和我們給他服用的重度抗生素
and the heavy-duty antibiotics we're giving him,
會造成永久性器官損傷
will cause permanent organ damage.
那就把他叫醒
Then wake him up.
什麼
Excuse me?
把約翰叫醒
Wake John up.
幫他停掉所有治療
Take him off of everything
讓我們的兒子自己與生命抗爭
and let our son fight for his life.
你剛說他服用的這些藥物
You just said these things that he's on
使他情況惡化
are making him worse.
即使約翰醒過來
And even if John wakes up,
我們清楚他可能永遠無法正常生活
we know he'll probably never live a normal life.
沒錯
That's right.
好的
Okay.
所以我們把他叫醒
So we wake him up.
好的
Okay.
我們將讓他停用所有藥物
Let's start tapering him off all medication.
明天早上  我們把他叫醒
Tomorrow morning, we wake him up.
我想我們需要幫助
I think we need to ask for help.
所有我們能獲得的幫助
All the help that we can get.
我們今晚得知約翰需要
We're hearing tonight that another miracle
另一場奇跡
is needed for John.
他仍在昏迷中
He is still in a coma,
他仍在與生命抗爭
and he is still fighting for his life.
喬伊絲·斯密斯
Joyce Smith,
約翰的母親
John's mother,
無法離開他兒子
was unable to leave her son's side.
但他們的家庭牧師傑森·諾貝爾
But the family's pastor, Jason Noble,
今晚就在我的旁邊
is joining me here tonight,
他想代表這個家庭
with something he'd like to say
說幾句話
on the family's behalf.
傑森
Jason.
在約翰的治療上
We've reached a critical juncture
我們面臨關鍵抉擇
in John's care.
因此史密斯一家要拜託大家一件事
So the Smith family simply asks for one thing.
請為約翰祈禱
So please pray for John.
他母親喬伊絲
His mother, Joyce,
相信上帝無所不能
believes that God can do the impossible.
因此讓我們向上帝祈禱
So we're asking Him to do just that.
謝謝
Thank you.
今晚史密斯一家需要
So the Smith family is in need
你們的祈禱
of your prayers tonight,
因為他們面臨這場極度嚴峻的考驗
as they face this incredibly difficult ordeal.
當我們首度報道約翰的事跡時
When we first reported on John's story,
我們感受到了
we got such an outpouring
社會湧現的關懷與憂慮
of care and concern from the community.
他的事跡不斷觸動了許多人
His story continues to touch so many lives.
我們將努力讓你們得知
And we are committed to keeping you posted
每一步進展
every step of the way.
我們的思想與祈禱與你同在  約翰
Our thoughts and prayers are with you, John.
這是凱·奎因在
This is Kay Quinn reporting
卡迪納爾格倫農醫院醫院為您現場報道
from Cardinal Glennon Hospital.
接下來把時間交回演播室
Back to you in the studio.
上帝  明天請在約翰的肺中
Lord, fill John's lungs tomorrow
注入生命的氣息
with the breath of life.
如您所願  讓他完全恢復
Restoring him fully if it be Your will.
□ 您在水面呼喚我 □
□ You call me out upon the waters □
□ 面對巨大的未知雙腳會迷失方向 □
□ The great unknown where feet may fail □
□ 我在神秘世界中發現了您 □
□ And there I find You in the mystery □
□ 在茫茫深海中 □
□ In oceans deep □
□ 我的信仰不曾動搖 □
□ My faith will stand □
□ 我會呼喚您的名字 □
□ And I will call upon Your name □
布萊恩
Brian.
□ 我的視線始終越過海浪 □
□ And keep my eyes above the waves □
□ 漲潮時  我將靈魂將投入您的懷抱 □
□ When oceans rise, my soul will rest in Your embrace □
□ 因為我屬於您 □
□ For I am Yours □
□ 您也屬於我 □
□ And You are mine □
□ 心靈引領著我  我的信念無邊無界 □
□ Spirit lead me where my trust is without borders □
□ 讓我漫步水上 □
□ Let me walk upon the waters □
□ 無論您在何處呼喚我 □
□ Wherever You would call me □
約翰
John.
你認識的所有人都在窗外
I think everybody you know is outside that window.
□ 將我帶去比雙腳能觸及的更深處 □
□ Take me deeper than my feet could ever wander □
□ 我的信仰會更強烈 □
□ And my faith will be made stronger □
□ 在我的拯救者面前 □
□ In the presence of my Savior □
□ 心靈引領著我  我的信念無邊無界 □
□ Spirit lead me where my trust is without borders □
□ 讓我漫步水上 □
□ Let me walk upon the waters □
□ 無論你在何處呼喚我 □
□ Wherever You would call me □
□ 將我帶去比雙腳能觸及的更深處 □
□ Take me deeper than my feet could ever wander □
對不起
I'm sorry...
我為我對你說的一切表示道歉
for all the things that I said to you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我應該一直留在這裡
I should've always been right here.
留在約翰身邊
By John's side.
留在你身邊
And yours.
□ 此地  此刻 □
□ Right here, right now □
□ 無論如何 □
□ Someway, somehow □
□ 此刻  我們需要您 □
□ Right now, we need You □
□ 我們不能沒有您 □
□ We can't do it without You □
□ 此地  此刻 □
□ Right here, right now □
□ 無論如何 □
□ Someway, somehow □
□ 此刻  我們需要您 □
□ Right now, we need You □
□ 我們不能沒有您 □
□ We can't do it without You □
□ 此地  此刻 □
□ Right here, right now □
□ 無論如何 □
□ Someway, somehow □
□ 我會呼喚您的名字 □
□ I will call upon Your name □
□ 還有 □
□ And... □
□ 我的視線始終越過海浪 □
□ Keep my eyes above the waves □
□ 漲潮時  我的靈魂將投入您的懷抱 □
□ When oceans rise, my soul will rest in Your embrace □
□ 因為我屬於您 □
□ For I am Yours □
□ 您也屬於我 □
□ And You are mine □
湯米
Tommy?
我要感謝你救了我兒子
I just wanna thank you for saving my son.
我只是做了本職工作
I was just doing my job.
我希望他能好起來
I hope he's gonna be okay.
2015年1月22日
約翰出事72小時後
我會給你們一些私密時間
I'm gonna give you guys some privacy.
這畢竟是你們家的事
This feels like a family thing.
如果你們需要我  我就在大廳裡
So I'm gonna be right down the hall if you need me.
的確是家事
It is a family thing.
所以我想你應該留下來
So I think you should stay.
是的
Yeah.
好
Okay.
大家準備好了嗎
Is everybody ready?
好
Okay.
首先從呼吸機開始
Let's start with the breathing treatment.
這將有助打開他的呼吸道和肺部
This is going to help open his airways and lungs.
然後我們能取出呼吸管
And then we can remove the breathing tube.
我們將拔出約翰的呼吸管
We're gonna extubate John.
約翰的肺部少部分出現萎縮
John's lungs have partially collapsed,
因此接下去的步驟不會輕鬆
so this next part won't be easy.
退後一點  好嗎
Move back a little bit, okay?
好的
Okay.
保持有序
Orderly.
他還好嗎  怎麼回事
Is he okay? What is happening?
喬伊絲
Joyce!
讓他聽聽你的聲音
Let him hear your voices.
約翰  這是你的爸爸媽媽
John, it's Mom and Dad.
兒子  我們與你同在
We're here for you, son.
一切都正常  我們就在這裡
Everything's okay. We're right here.
約翰  我們就在這
John, we're right here.
我愛你  約翰
I love you. John?
供氧
Oxygen.
開始輸氧  醫生
Starting the flow, Doctor.
好了  很好
Hmm. Okay, all right.
好了  他在自己呼吸
All right, he's breathing on his own.
好  我們給他注射鈉洛酮
Okay, let's get him the Narcan.
鈉洛酮  用於復合麻醉藥術後  解除呼吸抑制及催醒
0.4毫克
0.4 milligrams, please.
這將使約翰在幾分鐘內
This should kick-start John into consciousness
恢復意識
within the next few minutes,
然後我們就知道我們怎麼辦了
and then we'll see what we're dealing with.
這是人類能做到的極限了
This went about as well as humanly possible.
太糟糕了
That was awful.
-流程就是這樣  喬伊絲  -好的
- This is the process, Joyce. - Okay.
現在我們要等待
Now, we wait.
約翰
John.
約翰  寶貝
John, baby.
我要你振作起來
I need you to fight.
約翰
John.
你現在要回到我們身邊  約翰
You need to come back to us now, John.
我要你振作起來
I need you to fight.
你能行的  約翰
You can do it, John.
你現在要回到我們身邊  約翰
You need to come back to us now, John.
你有自己的目標  也有人愛著你
You have a purpose and you are loved.
我要你振作起來
I need you to fight.
約翰
John?
Oh, John!
你沒事了  約翰
You're okay, John.
約翰  我們就在這裡
Hey, John. We're right here.
一切都沒事了
Everything's okay.
約翰
Hey, John.
你能聽懂我的話嗎
Can you understand what I'm saying?
-你沒事了  約翰  -是爸爸媽媽
- You're okay, John. - It's Mom and Dad.
大家都在這裡
And everyone's here.
大家都在這裡  你遭遇了意外
Everyone's here. You had an accident.
你知道我是誰嗎
Do you know who I am?
我愛你
I love you.
媽
Ma.
約翰
John.
我在這
I'm here.
我就在這
I'm right here.
我在這  寶貝  我在這
I'm here, baby. I'm here.
在1985年  道格拉斯寫道
And in 1885, Douglass wrote
弗雷德裡克·道格拉斯的生命故事
Narrative of the Life of Frederick Douglass.
成為了著名文學體裁中最傑出的例子
And it became the preeminent example of the literary genre known...
約翰醒了
John is awake!
他的媽媽說他能說話了
His mom says he's talking.
老鐵們  他的媽媽說他能說話了
Guys, his mom says he's talking!
媽呀
Oh, my gosh!
約翰醒了
John's awake!
約翰醒了  約翰醒了  約翰醒了
John is awake! John is awake! John is awake!
媽呀
Oh, my God!
約翰醒了
John is awake!
約翰·史密斯醒了
John Smith is awake!
我再說一遍   約翰·史密斯醒了
I repeat, John Smith is awake!
吸氣
Breathe.
再來一次
Again.
One more time.
你的肺部非常乾淨
Your lungs are very clear.
你的氧氣水平上升了
Your oxygen levels are up.
-加勒特醫生  -咋啦
- Doctor Garrett? - Yes?
約翰的肺部培養物對細菌呈陰性
John's lung cultures came back negative for bacteria.
那就請再做一次
Run them again, please.
我已經試過了
Uh, I already did.
那是好事嗎
Is that a good thing?
那確實是一件特棒的好事  親愛的
That's a really good thing, honey.
溫迪  你願意幫助年輕的約翰
Wendy, would you help young John
做呼吸練習嗎
with his breathing exercises?
當然了
Absolutely.
當溫迪做好準備時
When Wendy's ready,
我要你做深呼吸
I want you to breathe in deeply,
我們才能測試你的肺活量
so we can test your lung capacity.
都聽你的
Whatever you need.
都聽我的
"Whatever I need."
喬伊絲
Joyce.
48小時前
Forty-eight hours ago,
約翰的肺部充血
John's lungs were filled with his own blood.
他要持續注射腎上腺素來維持心臟跳動
He needed constant adrenaline just to keep his heart pumping.
他的白細胞正消耗殆盡
His white blood cells were being consumed
比我見過的任何病人都快
faster than any patient I've ever seen.
他的大腦在神經性衰竭的同時
His brain was experiencing neurological devastation,
他的每一個主要器官
while simultaneously every one of his major organs...
也在衰竭
was failing.
但是現在  瞧瞧他
Now, look at him.
作為一個醫生
I'm a doctor.
我應該有更深入的瞭解
I'm supposed to know better.
但是真的沒有其他的解釋了  喬伊絲
But there's simply no other explanation, Joyce.
你的兒子是個奇跡
Your son's a miracle.
謝謝
Thank you.
驚喜來了
Surprise!
謝謝
Thank you.
天吶
Oh, my goodness.
那是啥
What's that?
我的天
Oh, my God!
太棒了
So cool!
我現在還不太能玩
Oh, I can't grip it yet.
你好  阿比
Hey, Abby.
你好  約翰
Hey, John.
別鬧  謝拉  好不咯
Shut it, Chayla. Come on.
（倒計時）2  1
Two, one.
兩周後
2015年2月16日
約翰出事28天後
你好  約翰
Hey, John!
歡迎回來  老鐵
Welcome back, man!
約翰
John!
歡迎回來  約翰
Welcome back, John.
謝謝  阿爾伯特老師
Thank you, Mrs. Abbott.
謝謝
Thank you.
好了  各位同學  我們翻到歷史書
Okay, everyone, let's turn to Chapter 19
第十九章
in our history books.
-阿爾伯特老師  -咋啦
- Mrs. Abbott? - Yeah.
我想我有很多漏的課程要補上
I know I have a lot to catch up on.
哎呀  約翰  你不用擔心啦
Oh, no, John. Please, don't worry about it.
老師非常高興能看到你回來
I'm just glad to have you back.
謝謝
Thank you.
你好  約翰
Hey, John.
我一直在尋思著
Uh, I was wondering,
你說為什麼
Why do you think...
上帝選擇拯救一部人而放棄另一部分人
God chooses to save some and not others?
是因為
It's just...
兩年前我失去了我的丈夫
I lost my husband two years ago.
他得了動脈瘤
He had an aneurysm...
死在睡夢中
and died in his sleep.
我竭力從陰影中走出來
And I'm still trying to figure it all out.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不  該道歉的是我
No, I'm sorry.
我不知道我在想啥
I don't know what I was thinking.
或者說  我壓根沒想啥
Clearly, I wasn't thinking.
為啥你不去找你的朋友嘮嘮嗑
Why don't you go and catch up with the rest of your friends?
我們下次再聊  好嗎
I'll see you tomorrow. Okay?
約翰  為什麼你這麼幸運
而我的媽媽死了
你好  奇跡男孩
What's up, Miracle Boy?
你打算上哪去
Where you running off to?
不打算再去冰面上走一遭嗎  約翰
Not gonna go try and, uh, walk on water again, are you, John?
湯米
Tommy?
湯米·希恩
Tommy Shine?
約翰
John?
能見到你真是太好了
It's good to finally meet you.
嗯吶
Yeah.
我也是
You too.
我剛剛坐在這想這是不是
I was just sitting here debating on whether...
命中注定的巧合
coincidences happen in life.
謝謝你救了我
Thank you for saving me.
我並沒有拯救你
I didn't save you, John.
我是說  既是我  也不是我
I mean, I did, but I didn't.
你掉進水裡的那天
In the water that day,
我都快要放棄你了  哥們
I was ready to give up on you, man.
但在那時我聽到一個聲音在喊我
But then I hear this voice telling me
往回走
"Go back."
上帝指引我去哪找你
God told me where to find you.
如果存在上帝的話
Well, if there's a God...
我不知道祂對你的安排是什麼
I don't know what he's got planned for you,
但一定有特殊的禮遇
but it must be something pretty special.
可能對於我倆都是這樣
Maybe that's true for the both of us.
就在那邊嗎
Way over there?
對  就在那兒
Yeah, right there. Oh.
早上好
Good morning!
這個禮拜天我們為你們準備了小小的驚喜
We have a little bit of a surprise for you this Sunday.
2015年3月1日
我邀請了我的一位朋友
I'd like to ask a good friend of mine,
喬伊絲·斯密斯和他的家人一同上台
Joyce Smith, and her family, to join me up here.
我們愛你  約翰
We love you, John!
在這一行幹了這麼久
In all my years in ministry,
我是說  我從沒見過
I mean, I've never even seen anything
或者聽過像這樣的事
or heard of anything like this.
那麼  約翰  你還記得什麼
So, John, what do you remember?
這算測試嗎
Testing on?
我記得我醒了
Well, I do remember waking up.
首先看到的是
And the first thing I saw...
我的媽媽  握著我的手
was my mom, holding my hand.
告訴我一切安好
And letting me know that everything was gonna be okay.
當我是個嬰兒時  沒人要我
When I was a baby, and no one wanted me,
除了我的父母
my parents wanted me.
還有當沒人認為我能挺過來的時候
And when no one thought that I could make it back,
我的媽媽相信我能
my mom knew that I could.
媽媽
Mom...
我愛你
I love you.
爸爸
Dad...
我也愛你
I love you, too.
我愛你  約翰
I love you, John.
有些人問你為啥能活下來而其他人不能
And for those of you who ask why me...
我不知道
I don't know.
但是一位偉大的老師曾教過我
But a great teacher once told me,
往者不可諫
"Yesterday's not ours to recover,
來者猶可追
"but tomorrow is ours to win or lose."
最後  我要感謝上帝
Lastly, I just wanna thank the Lord.
我想起來個好主意  讓約翰
I thought it might be a good idea for John
見見他的那些救命的恩人
to meet some of the people responsible for saving his life.
如果你是文茨維爾消防局的一員
If you're part of the Wentzville Fire Department,
請你站起來好嗎
would you please stand?
如果你是一位緊急調度官
If you're an emergency dispatch officer
或者是一位救護技術員成員
or an EMT member,
請你站起來好嗎
could you please stand as well?
現在  如果你是 聖路易斯湖警察局的一份子
Now, if you're a member of the Lake Saint Louis Police Department,
請你站起來好嗎
could you please stand?
如果你是聖約瑟夫醫療隊的一份子
If you're part of the St. Joseph medical team,
請你站起來好嗎
could you stand?
如果你是卡迪納爾格倫農醫院醫療隊的一份子
And if you're part of the Cardinal Glennon medical team,
請你站起來好嗎
could you stand?
感謝你們孜孜不倦的服務
Thank you so much for your tireless service.
感謝你們的奉獻
For your sacrifice.
拜託你們多站一會兒
If you could remain standing,
我還想問問有哪些人
I'd like to ask anyone
在學校為約翰祈禱的  站起來
who prayed for John at school to stand.
在家為約翰祈禱的  站起來
I'd like anyone who prayed for him at home to stand.
有哪些人在這個教堂為約翰祈禱的
I'd like anyone who prayed for him
站起來
in this very church to stand.
謝謝你們  你們可以坐下了
Thank you. You can please be seated.
我想正如人們常說的
I think it's been said that love...
愛是世界上最強大的力量
is the most powerful force on this earth.
並且我和我的丈夫都認為
And my husband and I, we believe that...
沒有愛  我們便不能出彩
without love, we cannot flourish,
我們便不能成長
we cannot grow.
我們便不能在這世上找到立身之地
We cannot find our place in this world.
愛的力量  特別是上帝的愛
And the power of love, and God's love especially,
是獨一無二的東西
is truly the one and only thing
能夠讓任何事情變成可能
that makes all things possible.
謝謝你們愛著約翰
Thank you for loving John,
謝謝你們愛著我們
and thank you for loving us.
十分感謝你們
Thank you so much.
謝謝
Thank you.
約翰  雄鷹隊  雄鷹隊
John! Eagle, eagle!
老鷹隊  老鷹隊
Eagle, eagle!